Samuel T. Betts Jr. Papers
Samuel T. Betts Jr. Papers
1934-1947
Betts, Samuel T., Jr., d. 1948.
4.5 linear ft.
Active member of civic organizations and owner of stamp and printing company. Collection contains correspondence, receipts, and photographs.
2750909
Biographical History
Samuel T. Betts Jr. (d. 1948) was a businessman in Skaneateles, New York. Betts was a long-time resident of Skaneateles and an active member of civic organizations such as the Skaneateles Library Association, Skaneateles Rotary Club, and on the board of appeals for the Village of Skaneateles. He was on the board of trustees for the Skaneateles Savings Bank and founded the Skaneateles Stamp Company, his main business venture.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Samuel T. Betts Jr. Papers contains correspondence, financial material, and memorabilia.
Correspondence consists of correspondence with family members and various clients of Betts' printing and stamp company, Skaneateles Stamp Co.
Financial material includes checks and bank statements from the National Bank and Trust Co. of Skaneateles and Betts' receipts, both personal and business.
Memorabilia consists of photographs of unknown individuals who could possibly be Betts's family, numerous calling cards and membership cards, souvenir postcards, and so on.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent, and within each folder chronologically. Financial material and memorabilia are arranged alphabetically by title, type, or topic.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; New York State; Business enterprises -- New York (State); Clubs.; Libraries -- New York (State); Stamp collecting.; Betts, Samuel T., Jr. -1948.; Rotary Club of Skaneateles (N.Y.); Addressograph-Multigraph Corporation.; White Plains Public Library (White Plains, N.Y.); Saugus Public Library (Saugus, Mass.); Alling & Cory Company.; Skaneateles (N.Y.); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Receipts (financial records); Photographs.; Postcards.; Bank statements.; Checks (bank checks); Business cards.; Visiting cards.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advance notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Unspecified, 1966.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Family, circa 1940 (Box 1)
  - Addressograph-Multigraph Corporation, 1939-1944 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Ross, Sr. and Jr., 1938-1944 (Box 1)
  - Baltimore Philatelic Society, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Libraries, 4 folders
    - Amityville Free Library, circa 1945 (Box 1)
    - Belmont Public library, circa 1945 (Box 1)
    - Brownsville Free Library, circa 1945 (Box 1)
    - Camden Free Public Library, circa 1945 (Box 1)
    - David A. How Public Library, circa 1945 (Box 1)
    - Jeannette Public Library, circa 1945 (Box 1)
    - Ripley Free Public Library, circa 1945 (Box 1)
    - Saugus Public LIbrary, circa 1945 (Box 1)
    - Scotia Public LIbrary, circa 1945 (Box 1)
    - White Plains Public Library, circa 1945 (Box 1)
    - Late card forms, circa 1945; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Late card form samples, circa 1945 (Box 2)
  - Postcards, 1934-1944; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Rotary Club, 1939-1944; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Skaneateles Country Club, 1938-1939; 1942,; 1945 (Box 3)
  - Skaneateles Stamp Company, 1938-1942; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Syracuse Stamp Club, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Washington Service, 1937-1940; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, A-L, 1938-1945; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, M-Z, 1938-1945; 2 folders (Box 4)
- Financial material
  - National Bank and Trust Co. of Skaneateles, 1940-1944; 1947; 9 folders; bank statements and checks (Box 4)
  - Receipts
    - A. J. Wright and Co., circa 1940 (Box 5)
    - Abbott, Proctor and Paine, circa 1940 (Box 4)
    - Addressograph-Multigraph Corporation, 1938-1944; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Alling and Cory Co., circa 1940 (Box 5)
    - Associate Laundries, 1938-1944 (Box 5)
    - Bentley and Thomas, 1938-1944 (Box 5)
    - J. and F. B. Garrett Co., 1938-1944 (Box 5)
    - Insurance, 1937-1947; package and car insurance (Box 5)
    - New York Telephone Company, 1937-1945 (Box 5)
    - Sands, J.D., M.D., 1940-1947 (Box 5)
    - Schicht System Shop, 1937-1945 (Box 5)
    - Stewart, Ivan J., 1939-1947 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, A-G, 1937-1947 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, H-W, 1937-1947; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1937-1947; handwritten notes, check stubs, membership reciepts, etc. (Box 6)
- Memorabilia
  - Business and calling cards (Box 6)
  - Membership cards, 1938-1944 (Box 6)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Photo postcards (Box 6)
  - Photographs, Betts family, others (Box 6)
  - Photographs, Betts family, others (Oversize 1)
  - Syracuse University 91st Commencement for the New York State College of Forestry, 1949; program (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, blank envelopes with addresses, event programs, handwritten notes, etc. (Box 6)